<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/classes/energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Energy on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 22:38:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.danioved.com/blog/classes/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Powered Analog Synthezier - Circuit Prototype and Power Budget</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/solar-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 22:38:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/solar-synth/</guid>
      <description>For this assigment for Energy, we are to power computation with solar power. I am collaborating with Fanni Fazakas, and we are going to create a solar powered analog synthesizer. This will take energy from the sun and convert it directly into sound waves via a low-power analog circuit.
Generating Sine, Square, and Triangle Waves We got a circuit design from Eric Rosenthal that can produce a sine, square and triangle wave:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Muscle Power into Usable Electricity</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/energy-generating-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 18:30:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/energy-generating-wheel/</guid>
      <description>For our Kinetic Energy assignment, with which I collaborated with Arnav Wagh, it was time to build something that would turn muscle power into usable electricity.
Selecting the Motor To power the lights, we would force a dc gear motor to turn and tap into the electricty it generates. We chose a 127 RPM Mini Econ Gear Motor from ServoCity, because it had optimal RPM and a low torque of 9,602 kgf-cm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts and Brainstorming</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 23:07:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/concepts/</guid>
      <description>For our Kinetic Energy assignment for the Energy class, I partnered up with Arnav. We came up with a few concepts for how to turn human motion into light.
Hand-Cranked Music Box The first thing we explored was turning a hand-crank music box into a music box that emits light.
  We would connect a motor to the end of the crank shaft and have that generate electricity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>