<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dan Oved&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dan Oved&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Physical Interaction?</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/what-is-physical-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/what-is-physical-interaction/</guid>
      <description>According to Chris Crawford in The Art of Interactive Design, Physical interaction is where a human interfaces with another entity, such as a person or computer, and that entity responds based on that action. It must be two-way; uni-directional communication is not interaction.
Examples of physical interaction:
 Typing in a text editor and seeing letters appearing. Painting with hand-help controllers in virtual reality. Having a conversation with another person. Playing a competitive sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Example of Good Design</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/an-example-of-good-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/an-example-of-good-design/</guid>
      <description>This last Sunday I was at a rooftop party at Output in Williamsburg and noticed my friend drinking what looked like a perfectly refreshing beverage – a can of Babe Rosé. Before even tasting her drink I decided to get one for myself, figuring it would be the perfect drink to enjoy during the sunset. In retrospect – the sleek, clean, and elegant design of the slender can is what lured me in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally fulfilling a ten-year-old goal of starting a blog and posting something.</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/about-writing-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/about-writing-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Today was the final day of orientation for ITP. Thanks goes out to the residents for giving us great workshops on creating documentation and how to create a blog, then forcing us do it.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to since I started coding, but each time my fear of public writing has turned into infinite procrastination.
One of the biggest takeaways from this talk is that even if you build something amazing, if no one sees and learns from it, then it&amp;rsquo;s pretty wasteful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>