<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Language on Dan Oved&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/tags/visual-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Language on Dan Oved&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oveddan.github.io/blog/tags/visual-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Language - My Colors</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/my-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/my-colors/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment, we were tasked to pick a color scheme that represents us, and create six compositions using that scheme.
The Color Scheme I chose the theme inspired by Tame Impala &amp;lsquo;Currents&amp;rsquo; from The Day&amp;rsquo;s Color:
  
The Compositions These were all made using Adobe Illustrator, with the exception of Cornucopia, which was made with Processing.
Breadth   
Monet - Sunset in Venice</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expressive Words</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/expressive-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/expressive-words/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment we were to design 3 expressive words that visually communicate their meanings. Here is what I created:  
 Icons used: The Rest, Afro and cat from The Noun Project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redesigning the Delta Boarding Pass</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/boarding-pass-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/boarding-pass-redesign/</guid>
      <description>Original Design For this homework assignment we were to take the boarding pass below and redesign it:
 
My Redesign   Icons used: Door and Airplane Seat from The Noun Project
My design assumes that the passenger gets this boarding pass at the check-in counter or kiosk, and the stub on the right is torn off and handed to the passenger at the gate. The information hierarchy is organized to make it quick to find the most important information at every part of the way from the check-in counter to the seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Language - This Is a Good and Bad Sign</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/this-is-a-good-and-bad-sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/this-is-a-good-and-bad-sign/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment, we are to show two examples each of successful and unsuccessful signs, then redesign one of the bad signs.
Unsuccessful Signs V-Nam cafe, on 1st and 1st, is in my opinion the best Vietnamese restaurant in New York City. I used to live a block away and would walk by it all the time, but had no idea it existed until discovering it through Yelp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Example of Good Design</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/an-example-of-good-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/an-example-of-good-design/</guid>
      <description>This last Sunday I was at a rooftop party at Output in Williamsburg and noticed my friend drinking what looked like a perfectly refreshing beverage – a can of Babe Rosé. Before even tasting her drink I decided to get one for myself, figuring it would be the perfect drink to enjoy during the sunset. In retrospect – the sleek, clean, and elegant design of the slender can is what lured me in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>