<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Dan Oved&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Dan Oved&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:43:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oveddan.github.io/blog/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing my Business Card</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/business-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:43:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/visual_language/business-card/</guid>
      <description>For our final homework assignment in Visual Language, we were to design a logo and business card for ourselves.
Earlier in the semseter, when I heard that this would be our final project, I was both excited and terrified. This proved to be very challenging in the end. When it finally came time to work on this, I found myself frequently criticizing my designs, starting over, and letting out a highly audible sigh that made those around me chuckle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoetrope Light and Materials Exploration</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/zoetrope-light-and-materials-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 10:08:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/zoetrope-light-and-materials-exploration/</guid>
      <description>See Part 2 and Part 3 of this project.
 For our first project for Designing for Digital Fabrication, we are to create something using the laser cutter, with at least some of the geometry generated algebraically. We have two weeks to complete this.
Inspiration I searched for inspirations for a project like this and ended up discovering the Zoetrope and being blown away by what people have done with it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Digital Fabrication - Drawing a Real World Object in Vectorworks</title>
      <link>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/drawing-a-real-world-object-in-vectorworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oveddan.github.io/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/drawing-a-real-world-object-in-vectorworks/</guid>
      <description>Our first homework assignment for Daniel Rozin&amp;rsquo;s Designing for Digital Fabrication class was to draw three 2d perspectives of a real world object in Vectorworks. I took this as an opportunity to get the exact dimensions of an object I&amp;rsquo;ve been eager to to incorporate into a project.
At the Armory show in 2015, I discovered and was amazed by the low-resolution work of Jim Campbell.
Jim Campbell - Scattered 25X (Marathon)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>