<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronics on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/tags/electronics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Electronics on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 12:33:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.danioved.com/blog/tags/electronics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PCB Design</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 12:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-design/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assigment of Homemade Hardware, we were to &amp;ldquo;Create Eagle files for ATtiny85 sensor + LED.&amp;rdquo;
I decided to design a PCB for the Ultrasonic Distance Sensor breadboarded prototype from the previous week.
 The schematic design for connecting an HC-SR04 to an ATTiny85  Based on this design and our tutorial from the previous class, I created this schematic:
  When it came time to design the board, I wanted to be sure that the HC-SR04 Ultrasonic Distance sensor would be facing the outside of the board so that none of the board components would interfere with its signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hardware - Ultrasonic Distance Sensor Input</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/ultrasonic-distance-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 20:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/ultrasonic-distance-sensor/</guid>
      <description>For our first homework assignment for Homemade Hardware, we are to create a breadboard ATtiny project, using a sensor of your choosing that controls an LED. I chose the ultrasonic distance sensor, since I&amp;rsquo;ve never used it, and can see many uses for it.
Here is a hand-drawn schematic of how it would be hooked up to an ATTiny85:
 Input Schematic  And here is the ultrasonic distance sensor hooked up to the ATTiny85, controlling the brightness of an LED:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>