<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fabrication on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/tags/fabrication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fabrication on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 20:44:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.danioved.com/blog/tags/fabrication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PCB Circuit Fabrication With the Othermill</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-fabrication-with-othermill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 20:44:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-fabrication-with-othermill/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment for Homemade Hardware, we were to fabricate a PCB Board using the Othermill.
I continued with the previous design of an ATTiny85 controlling the brightness of an LED based on the reading from an HC-sr04 Ultrasonic Distance Sensor. I modified it slightly based on the instructions from class. A 1k resistor connect the reset pin of the ATTiny85 to the power, and the output LED pin would be connected via a TIP120 Transistor to the ground line of the LEDs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Muscle Power into Usable Electricity</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/energy-generating-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 18:30:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/energy-generating-wheel/</guid>
      <description>For our Kinetic Energy assignment, with which I collaborated with Arnav Wagh, it was time to build something that would turn muscle power into usable electricity.
Selecting the Motor To power the lights, we would force a dc gear motor to turn and tap into the electricty it generates. We chose a 127 RPM Mini Econ Gear Motor from ServoCity, because it had optimal RPM and a low torque of 9,602 kgf-cm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts and Brainstorming</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 23:07:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/concepts/</guid>
      <description>For our Kinetic Energy assignment for the Energy class, I partnered up with Arnav. We came up with a few concepts for how to turn human motion into light.
Hand-Cranked Music Box The first thing we explored was turning a hand-crank music box into a music box that emits light.
  We would connect a motor to the end of the crank shaft and have that generate electricity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating the Kinetic Sculpture</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/presence/fabricating-the-kinetic-sculpture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:30:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/presence/fabricating-the-kinetic-sculpture/</guid>
      <description>After prototyping fabricating a small version of Presence to test the design and physical mechanics, it was time to build the real thing.
I decided to go with a design of 21 tubes arranged tightly together in a curve.
They would be mounted on long piece of arcrylic attached at the bottom to a piece of CNC routed plywood:
For the sides, I designed walls with small .2&amp;rdquo; deep x .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating the Prototype</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/presence/fabricating-the-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 23:52:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/presence/fabricating-the-prototype/</guid>
      <description>For the first phase of the physical installation, I wanted to fabricate a basic prototype that prove out the form factor, mechanics of the motors, and strength of the frame.
The design for the full installation:
Originally, I wanted to use wooden dowels and paint the patterns on them. However, these proved to be heavy and expensive. A cheaper, lighter solution was to use shipping tubes. I could order 2&amp;rdquo;x48&amp;rdquo; order in bulk from Mcmaster Carr for $16 per 5 tubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Design, Bill of Materials and Schematics</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/presence/design-bom-schematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 15:38:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/presence/design-bom-schematics/</guid>
      <description>After doing play testing for Presence, I concluded that:
 Trying to make this a meditative experience would be challenging. It will be difficult enough to get the interation and gaze tracking right, so just create a experience that simply reacts to the users gaze. There should be, near-instantaneous, clear visuals showing where the user is gazing, instead of making a column and its surroundings turn blank gradually. Having the gaze represented in the y-axis when just rotating columns in the x-axis can be achieved with a spiral design similar to Daniel Rozin&amp;rsquo;s Twisted Strips  I came up with this design:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Diorama</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/weather-diorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 20:33:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/weather-diorama/</guid>
      <description>Background / Motivation This was my teams&amp;rsquo; project for our Intro to Physical Computing midterm, where we were encouraged to use serial communication. Barak Chamo and Mai Arakida Izsak were the other team members, and contributed to this post.
After seeing Barak create his initial Fuji Diorama:
We thought it would be interesting to insert lights between the layers that could change the appearance of the scene depend on the time of day or weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Zoetrope Animations</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/generating-zoetrope-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 13:25:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/generating-zoetrope-animations/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation of Part 1 of the Zeotrope project for my Design for Digital Fabrication class. The final phase can be seen in Part 3
The next step of the project was to prototype the mechanics of the animation. The main questions were:
 How many frames of animation are optimal? What should the rotation speed be? At what rate should the lights flash?  The Rotation Mechanism - a Turntable There were many examples of Zoetropes on the web - the majority of them used a turntable to rotate the animation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoetrope Light and Materials Exploration</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/zoetrope-light-and-materials-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 10:08:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/zoetrope-light-and-materials-exploration/</guid>
      <description>See Part 2 and Part 3 of this project.
 For our first project for Designing for Digital Fabrication, we are to create something using the laser cutter, with at least some of the geometry generated algebraically. We have two weeks to complete this.
Inspiration I searched for inspirations for a project like this and ended up discovering the Zoetrope and being blown away by what people have done with it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing a Real World Object in Vectorworks</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/drawing-a-real-world-object-in-vectorworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/drawing-a-real-world-object-in-vectorworks/</guid>
      <description>Our first homework assignment for Daniel Rozin&amp;rsquo;s Designing for Digital Fabrication class was to draw three 2d perspectives of a real world object in Vectorworks. I took this as an opportunity to get the exact dimensions of an object I&amp;rsquo;ve been eager to to incorporate into a project.
At the Armory show in 2015, I discovered and was amazed by the low-resolution work of Jim Campbell.
Jim Campbell - Scattered 25X (Marathon)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>