<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 20:44:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.danioved.com/blog/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PCB Circuit Fabrication With the Othermill</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-fabrication-with-othermill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 20:44:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-fabrication-with-othermill/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment for Homemade Hardware, we were to fabricate a PCB Board using the Othermill.
I continued with the previous design of an ATTiny85 controlling the brightness of an LED based on the reading from an HC-sr04 Ultrasonic Distance Sensor. I modified it slightly based on the instructions from class. A 1k resistor connect the reset pin of the ATTiny85 to the power, and the output LED pin would be connected via a TIP120 Transistor to the ground line of the LEDs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Muscle Power into Usable Electricity</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/energy-generating-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 18:30:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/energy-generating-wheel/</guid>
      <description>For our Kinetic Energy assignment, with which I collaborated with Arnav Wagh, it was time to build something that would turn muscle power into usable electricity.
Selecting the Motor To power the lights, we would force a dc gear motor to turn and tap into the electricty it generates. We chose a 127 RPM Mini Econ Gear Motor from ServoCity, because it had optimal RPM and a low torque of 9,602 kgf-cm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCB Design</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 12:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/pcb-design/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assigment of Homemade Hardware, we were to &amp;ldquo;Create Eagle files for ATtiny85 sensor + LED.&amp;rdquo;
I decided to design a PCB for the Ultrasonic Distance Sensor breadboarded prototype from the previous week.
 The schematic design for connecting an HC-SR04 to an ATTiny85  Based on this design and our tutorial from the previous class, I created this schematic:
  When it came time to design the board, I wanted to be sure that the HC-SR04 Ultrasonic Distance sensor would be facing the outside of the board so that none of the board components would interfere with its signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hardware - Ultrasonic Distance Sensor Input</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/ultrasonic-distance-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 20:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/homemade-hardware/ultrasonic-distance-sensor/</guid>
      <description>For our first homework assignment for Homemade Hardware, we are to create a breadboard ATtiny project, using a sensor of your choosing that controls an LED. I chose the ultrasonic distance sensor, since I&amp;rsquo;ve never used it, and can see many uses for it.
Here is a hand-drawn schematic of how it would be hooked up to an ATTiny85:
 Input Schematic  And here is the ultrasonic distance sensor hooked up to the ATTiny85, controlling the brightness of an LED:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts and Brainstorming</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 23:07:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/energy/kinetic-project/concepts/</guid>
      <description>For our Kinetic Energy assignment for the Energy class, I partnered up with Arnav. We came up with a few concepts for how to turn human motion into light.
Hand-Cranked Music Box The first thing we explored was turning a hand-crank music box into a music box that emits light.
  We would connect a motor to the end of the crank shaft and have that generate electricity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Diorama</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/weather-diorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 20:33:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/weather-diorama/</guid>
      <description>Background / Motivation This was my teams&amp;rsquo; project for our Intro to Physical Computing midterm, where we were encouraged to use serial communication. Barak Chamo and Mai Arakida Izsak were the other team members, and contributed to this post.
After seeing Barak create his initial Fuji Diorama:
We thought it would be interesting to insert lights between the layers that could change the appearance of the scene depend on the time of day or weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Zoetrope Animations</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/generating-zoetrope-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 13:25:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/design_for_digital_fabrication/generating-zoetrope-animations/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation of Part 1 of the Zeotrope project for my Design for Digital Fabrication class. The final phase can be seen in Part 3
The next step of the project was to prototype the mechanics of the animation. The main questions were:
 How many frames of animation are optimal? What should the rotation speed be? At what rate should the lights flash?  The Rotation Mechanism - a Turntable There were many examples of Zoetropes on the web - the majority of them used a turntable to rotate the animation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Loop</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/light-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/light-loop/</guid>
      <description>The Features The goal of this project is to use analog input and digital input to drive digital output.
This is accomplished by detecting when a photoresistor, an analog input, gets a certain amount of light. When that happens, it triggers an animation on the opposite end of the LEDS which travels through them back towards the photoresistor. When the photoresistor picks up enough light from the animation that has reached it, it triggers the start of the animation again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubling the Battery Power</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/batteries-in-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/physical_computing/batteries-in-parallel/</guid>
      <description>A project I worked on this past summer required a portable power source of 3.3 - 4 volts. I used the Tenergy Li-Ion 3.7v 2600 mAH rechargeable battery, connected to the Adafruit LiPoly backpack charger and a Teensy 3.2. In this system, the battery would be drained after only about half an hour; I wanted to increase the capacity but did not know how.
Then last week, for my Basic Analog Circuit course, I learned about connecting multiple batteries in parallel to maintain the same voltage but increase the current and capacity by connecting the powers and grounds together of the batteries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>