<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Language on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/classes/visual-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Language on Dan Oved&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:43:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.danioved.com/blog/classes/visual-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing my Business Card</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/business-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:43:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/business-card/</guid>
      <description>For our final homework assignment in Visual Language, we were to design a logo and business card for ourselves.
Earlier in the semseter, when I heard that this would be our final project, I was both excited and terrified. This proved to be very challenging in the end. When it finally came time to work on this, I found myself frequently criticizing my designs, starting over, and letting out a highly audible sigh that made those around me chuckle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design for the ITP Winter Show 2017 Show Postcard</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/show-postcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 02:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/show-postcard/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Colors and Compositions</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/my-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/my-colors/</guid>
      <description>For this Visual Language homework assignment, I was tasked to pick a color palette that represents me, and create six compositions using those colors.
The Color Palette I wanted a theme with red because this represents it represents love and life, and I believe in living a life doing what you love.
I chose the color palette inspired by Tame Impala &amp;lsquo;Currents&amp;rsquo; from The Day&amp;rsquo;s Color:
 These colors are both vibrant and diverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expressive Words</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/expressive-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/expressive-words/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment we were to design 3 expressive words that visually communicate their meanings. Here is what I created:  
 Icons used: The Rest, Afro and cat from The Noun Project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redesigning the Delta Boarding Pass</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/boarding-pass-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/boarding-pass-redesign/</guid>
      <description>Original Design For this homework assignment we were to take the boarding pass below and redesign it:
 
My Redesign   Icons used: Door and Airplane Seat from The Noun Project
My design assumes that the passenger gets this boarding pass at the check-in counter or kiosk, and the stub on the right is torn off and handed to the passenger at the gate. The information hierarchy is organized to make it quick to find the most important information at every part of the way from the check-in counter to the seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Language - This Is a Good and Bad Sign</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/this-is-a-good-and-bad-sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/this-is-a-good-and-bad-sign/</guid>
      <description>For this homework assignment, we are to show two examples each of successful and unsuccessful signs, then redesign one of the bad signs.
Unsuccessful Signs V-Nam cafe, on 1st and 1st, is in my opinion the best Vietnamese restaurant in New York City. I used to live a block away and would walk by it all the time, but had no idea it existed until discovering it through Yelp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Example of Good Design</title>
      <link>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/an-example-of-good-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.danioved.com/blog/posts/visual_language/an-example-of-good-design/</guid>
      <description>This last Sunday I was at a rooftop party at Output in Williamsburg and noticed my friend drinking what looked like a perfectly refreshing beverage – a can of Babe Rosé. Before even tasting her drink I decided to get one for myself, figuring it would be the perfect drink to enjoy during the sunset. In retrospect – the sleek, clean, and elegant design of the slender can is what lured me in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>